MICHELLE STERMITZ

FRONTEND SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

I'm a passionate, design-oriented frontend developer dedicated to creating thoughtful user experiences and visually appealing, responsive applications. Drawing from my full stack experience, consulting background and love of collaboration, I bring designs to life while prioritizing optimal performance and accessibility for all users.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Software Engineer, Powell's City of Books, Portland, OR

01/2024 - Present

- · Collaborated with a newly formed engineering team to launch a greenfield, large-scale e-commerce platform
- · Led Storybook integration for responsive, atomic design; served as the primary owner to drive consistent component use
- · Owned UX, UI, and accessibility improvements across the site, from layout to interaction patterns
- · Monitored performance, analytics, and error tracking to support site stability and user experience

Personal Sabbatical 03/2023 - 10/2023

I took a personal sabbatical to focus on both personal and professional growth, and to level up as a developer. During that time, I built a full stack interview prep app using the OpenAl API, started dreaming up my color scheme app, and picked up several new technical skills.

Software Engineer, Olio Apps, Portland, OR

05/2021 - 03/2023

- Independently developed the frontend for two React Native mobile apps, including a barometric pressure tracker for the EarPlanes
 product line
- · Led a three-person team for Solar Redline, a "Yelp for solar panel installation," managing tickets, workflow, and release priorities
- Heavily contributed to the frontend development of Carbon Title, a carbon reduction platform, focusing on technical design, sprint planning, and project board management
- · Specialized in atomic design and trained team members in Storybook-driven development for scalable, consistent UI components
- · Collaborated directly with clients on testing, debugging, and iterating based on feedback

Graphic Designer, Marketing, Personal Assistant, Freelance

2017 - 2019

Upheld mission of professional brands via graphic design, Wordpress editing, keyword mapping and other tasks. Expanded skillset in accordance with business needs and sought feedback in order to deliver high quality product.

Graphic Designer, Manager, The Stensrud Playhouse, Missoula, MT

2013 - 2017

As co-founder of The Stensrud Playhouse, an event venue, I delivered successful marketing plans resulting in sold-out shows. I strengthened the relationship with the community by developing a large social media following and website. I managed sales, box office, kitchen operations and staff, and designed all paper and digital materials.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript/Typescript, HTML, CSS

Frontend: React, Vue, Next.js, React Native, Storybook, Tailwind, Nuxt, Styled Components, Bootstrap, Material UI,

GraphQL, Vuetify

Backend: Node.js, Firebase, PostgreSQL, Prisma

Tools, Testing and Services: Github, Figma, Vercel, Netlify, Heroku, Postman, Hasura, Datadog, CommerceTools, Algolia

EDUCATION

Alchemy Code Lab, Portland, OR, Fullstack JavaScript Certificate

2020

800+ hour full stack software development program. JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, and PostgreSQL with an emphasis on test-driven development and collaboration.

Santa Monica College, Santa Monica, CA University of Canterbury, Christchurch, NZ 2010 - 2012

2010